

Paulo Vatchara Yuvanasiri

Head of IT Document & Knowledge Center at Siam Commercial Bank

51/1 Soi Sukhumvit 62/1 Bangchak Prakaonong Bangkok 10260 Thailand

Mobile: 089-115-4545 paulovatchara@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Motivated, results-driven with more than ten years of vast experience in multinational company 5 years in the financial industry and with 8 years of experience in fast moving telecom industries. Major strengths in presenting, managing, coordinating, planning and organizing. Additional skills in interpersonal, negotiation and problem solving. A well-organized and pragmatic person who is a strong communicator capable of maintaining customer relationships.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Siam Commercial Bank Head of IT Document and Knowledge Center

2015-Present

- Set strategic direction to uplift technical skills as well as banking product knowledge to application developers
- Develop application developers to anticipate and understand conflicts and overcome barriers that impact Application Development Projects and cross functional team collaboration
- Build future leaders of IT Development Division to meet current and future organization goals.
- Ensure the content and materials used in training programs are up to date and appropriately in line with IT Development Division's Strategic Training Plan.
- Supervise the members of the IT Knowledge Development Center department team to ensure they are meeting the goals of the Training Strategic Plan and are in compliance with SCB policies and procedures.
- Supervisory responsibilities include interviewing, hiring, training employees, planning, assigning and directing work, appraising performance, rewarding and counseling employees, addressing complaints/issues and resolving problems.

TMB Bank PCL Team Lead Digital Communications

2009-2015

- Lead implementation knowledge management platform (Microsoft Sharepoint 2013)
- Lead/execute digital development & content rollout strategies for internal/external digital platform
- Project Leader development digital concept www.MakeTHEDifference.org

- Create and implement social media facebook/TMBMakeTHEDifference
- Launch internal campaign "Make THE Difference" for internal staff
- Implement internal digital TMB Parkrun campaign
- Co-ordinating with cross functional department e.g. Marketing and Commercial and IT to provide requirement for new intranet system
- Revamp TMB Intranet to be the first bank that use social collaboration intranet system with more than 7000 users/day
- Identify resolutions for day-to-day problems encountered by intranet's developer
- Initiate Management roadshow digital channels for staff to booked sessions on-line
- · Co-ordinate the launch of Internal Digital magazine

True Corporation 2008-2009 Assistant Director, Knowledge Management Center

Concept Shop Project "True innovation Digital Library"

- Project Leader of True Innovation Library @ Digital Gateway Siam
- · Contact digital content provider platform and generate new interactive ideas
- Create, evaluate and analyze proposals for Digital Library, new multi-touch display concept

iPhone 3G launching program

- · Lead in Product Training Program for Launching iPhone 3G
- Build up "True Staff" Product Support Team for iPhone 3G, provide product knowledge support to customer and back support
- Provide intranet website knowledge support for customer touch point

True Corporation 2007-2008 Assistant Director, CM Knowledge Management and Business Solutions (Customer Management Department)

- Responsible for heading Customer Management Business Solutions Unit (Business Project Management, Business Process and Knowledge Management) in developing initiatives to improve operational support
- Lead supporting team to achieve business convergent strategy
- Perform impact assessment before launch of commercial propositions with relevant team
- Develop new communications tools to support all call center site (Mobile, Internet, Cable, Fixed Line)
- · Provide status readiness of the project, process and KM information for all call center
- Develop and analyze weekly, monthly, supporting strategy and action plan
- Co-ordinating with cross functional department e.g. Marketing and Commercial and IT to provide impact assessment in launching new product concept
- Ensure the flow of call center process operation complete within timeline and smoothness
- · Initiate concept of Web TV interface for Call Center

True Corporation 2005–2006

System Support Manager (Customer Experience Relationship Management Department)

Branding Shop Project "True Urban Park at Siam Paragon"

- Project Manager of True Urban Park at Siam Paragon
- Be a team member to implement and design strategy for True's Branding Store Project
- Co-ordinate with Business partner to set up Branding store
- Provide status readiness of the project, system and staff to Management
- Lead operation and ensure that operation will efficiently operate
- · Lead Shop operation and ensure that the system will efficient operate
- Work closely with HR Department in recruitment process
- Identify resolutions for day-to-day project management
- Developing and initiating "True Staff" counter advising, and consulting service to customer

Motive Project (Customer Broadband Care)

- Member of project manager team in implementing customer broad band care
- Work closely with Leading Outsourcing team (capture user's requirement)
- Provide Test Scenario script for user to monitor software performance
- Team leader in designing usability of software (look and feel)
- · Work closely with Marketing team in launching customer broadband care

10 Digits Project

- Project leader in developing solutions software for mobile phone user (9digits 10digits)
- Develop Micro-site to support customer
- Provide alternative solutions platform "Palm, PPC, Symbian and Outlook"
- Responsible in heading in Road show of 10 Digits conversion tools
- Closely monitor feedback report to management

True Corporation / TA Orange Co., Ltd

2004-2005

CeRM Development Manager

- Co-ordinate with True Life Style Team in launching new retail store concepts
- Building up IT-Expert Team to capture product knowledge
- Design product concept road map True Life Style Store.
- Co-ordinate with strategic consultant in developing CRM platform.
- Initiate new product concept (broadband care) for True ADSL customer to expand business opportunities of e-Commerce.
- Discovery potential CRM readiness for True, Orange and Asianet.
- Work closely with worldwide consultants in discovery phase of CRM program.
- Provide strategic suggestions to management by introducing Laboratory room for Internet call center training.

Communications Development Manager

- Participate in developing strategic planning for integration of knowledge management in the affiliate companies.
- Plan and co-ordinate with internal workflow, content and training in launching new product and service.
- Ensure customer complaints and recommendations are handled in effective and timely fashion. Feedbacks are being provided to support the quality of calls.

Communications Supervisor

- Lead and Supervise for Reference tool team to achieve the mission and project plan.
- Ensure that reliable and consistent information are communicated to customers across all customer contact channel.
- Organize CM internal events to provide information to CM staff as well as to create an enjoyable workplace to strengthen teamwork.
- Serve as in-house agency to develop / produce communications work for Customer Management Department.
- Responsible all multimedia production tasks and process such as CM Sports day event Unseen Network documentary for Orange employee.
- Monitor feedback received regarding the system, coordinating the changes to the system as appropriate also ensure customers and call centre complaints, suggestions and recommendations are handled in effective and timely fashion. Feedbacks are being provided to support the quality of calls.

Intranet Technical Author

- Provide full support reference information for call center in web base format
- · Design and develop web view layout for Reference Tool with User-friendly Design, add easy to use functionality on knowledge management system.
- Co-ordinate with cross-functional team to develop content in knowledge management system.

Oyeah net (Australia)

2000-2001

Web Designer

- · Founder of oyeah.com.au
- Initiate a graphical logo, look and feel of the website.
- Co-ordinate with strategic partner in setting up free e-mail base, forum and banners link.

EDUCATION

♦ Central Queensland University (Australia)

1999-2001

Master of Business Administration Master of Information System

Assumption University

1993-1997

Bachelor of Business Administration Major: Marketing

◆ Trium Udom Suksa Pattanakarn High School

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

- Microsoft sharepoint 2013
- ♦ iOS Apple
- ♦ Cool Town (HP) Singapore site visit
- Project Management work shop
- ♦ Call handling strategy work shop
- ♦ Macromedia studio MX seminar
- ♦ IBM Web sphere Training

ACCOMPLISHMENT

- Launch project Knowledge Management Microsoft Sharepoint
- ♦ Implement Social Intranet system (First bank in Thailand)
- ◆ Make THE Difference Digital Campaign and Digital Platform
- ♦ Revamp New TMB Intranet system
- ◆ Launch iPhone 3G Training Program and Intranet Knowledge Support
- ◆ Launch True Branding Store (True Urban park) Siam Paragon
- Manage product concept and customer service support for True Life Style shop.
- Pilot study Internet call center and make strategic recommendation for top management. Increase efficiency of total business process flow.
- ♦ Support knowledge management system on the basis of all contents existing in on systems. Being used by front-line staff mostly, all information is supposed to be accurate, updated and accessible.
- Plan and manage the impact of the launch of Orange SPV Phone.
- Conduct the Design and develop web view layout for Reference Tool with User-friendly Design, add easy to use functionality on knowledge management system. Create knowledge transfer and reduce training cost.
- ◆ Introduce new media center content on Orange's Knowledge Management System. Provide new video media for customer service staff. Develop and implement multimedia-streaming solution.
- ◆ Design and develop Knowledge Management System for Orange Content for call center

SKILLS AND OTHERS

- ◆ Language: English/ Thai
- ♦ **Software Skill:** Microsoft Office, Photoshop, Illustrator, PageMaker, Microsoft Project, DreamWeaver, Visio, Mind jet X5, Basic Programming
- ◆ Computer Hardware in depth knowledge in Desktop Computer assembly, Palm, Pocket PC, Smart phone, and special gadgets, iPhone

Personal Data

Date of birth 26 November 1974

Marital status Married